(Level 1 Demon Lord and One Room Hero)
《Lv1魔王與獨居廢勇者》
(Episode 7: The Secretary is Struggling) Zenia, we're back.
(#7 秘書官奮鬥中) 潔妮亞 我們回來了
-Strange. -What's up?
-真奇怪 -怎麼啦
Zenia does not appear to be at home.
潔妮亞好像不在家
Normally, if I call her, she will come right away.
平常只要朕呼喚她 她就會立刻趕來
Did she go shopping in that odd outfit?
她是不是穿那身怪衣服出門買東西了
I asked her to look into something before we left on our journey.
我們出遠門之前朕還拜託她調查事情
Don't even think about sneaking a bite of souvenirs!
喂 不准你偷吃土產啦
First come, first serve.
先搶先贏
I am also craving buns.
朕也要吃饅頭
Zenia, we'll be out for about two days.
潔妮亞 我們要外出兩天左右
During this time, please take care of things for us…
在這段期間要麻煩妳…
Look into the Magic Bureau, where Fred works.
調查弗雷德任職的魔導廳
Understood, leave it to me.
遵命 屬下明白了 包在屬下身上
So this is the Magic Bureau.
這裡就是魔導廳
It is a vital national body in charge of overseeing
不僅管理王國的魔法能源產業
the kingdom's magical energy industry
同時也掌管相關軍事勢力的
MAGIC BUREAU
(魔導廳)
and related military forces.
重要國家機關
I can see why His Majesty wants to look into the Magic Bureau.
我能理解陛下為何想調查魔導廳
I will complete the mission regardless.
我無論如何都要圓滿達成任務
It appears impossible to infiltrate through the main entrance.
看來不可能從正門入侵
But don't dismiss me as a simple secretary.
但是別以為我只是普通的秘書
I will enter the Magic Bureau from the back, where there are fewer windows.
我先繞到窗戶較少的魔導廳後側
Zenia's special seven spy tools,
潔妮亞特製七大間諜道具
grapple hook.
鉤繩
Go!
去吧
The grapple hook snags.
鉤繩勾住了
Sneak in from the roof to avoid being seen.
從屋頂入侵以避人耳目
This is the common sense way of being a spy.
這可是當間諜的常識
What's that?
那是什麼
Naturally, the roof's door is locked.
屋頂的門當然是鎖著的
But now it is time to use
不過這種時候
the second of the seven tools, the lockpick.
就要拿七大道具之二 撬鎖工具
I will use this
我要用這個…
to pick the lock…
撬開鎖…
The invasion was a success.
入侵成功
Who are you?
妳誰啊
Remove any witnesses as soon as possible.
迅速除掉目擊者
This is also a spy rule.
這也是間諜的鐵則
But His Majesty once said that
不過以前陛下如此說過…
humans are not like us demons.
人類與我等魔之眷屬不同
They are unable to reawaken from the dead.
他們無法從死之長眠甦醒過來
Therefore, we must not kill humans without cause. Do you get it?
因此我們不能濫殺人類 你們懂了嗎
Your Majesty is so cool.
陛下好帥
You should thank His Majesty.
你就好好感謝陛下吧
I won't take your life.
我不會取走你的命
Hello.
妳好
May I ask who you--
請問是哪位…
It seems like I run into people here more often than I thought.
這裡比我想的更容易撞見別人
I should enter through the ventilation duct.
我還是走通風口吧
My only goal is to gather information.
我的目的只是蒐集情報
Normally, the data room or server room
能取得情報的地方
is where I can get information.
不外乎是資料室或電腦機房
THIRD OF THE SEVEN TOOLS, ENERGY JELLY I will mark these locations for investigation.
(七大道具之三 能量果凍) 我就鎖定這幾個地方調查吧
His Majesty will be overjoyed
只要我能帶回魔導廳的資料
if I can bring back the Magic Bureau's data.
陛下肯定會龍心大悅
Cafeteria.
餐廳
Toilet.
廁所
I found it. It's the server room.
我找到了 是電腦機房
It's so cold.
冷死了
There's only one staff member here.
這裡只有一位職員
I need to deal with him first.
我先想辦法解決他
Fourth of the seven tools, Hypnosis Dart.
七大道具之四 催眠吹箭
What's this?
這是啥
Problem solved.
解決
Alright, now let's get to the main point.
好了 現在才要進入正題
The fifth of the seven tools,
七大道具之五
hacker tool.
駭客工具
There's a lot of data here. This might take a while.
這資料量很龐大 恐怕會花上不少時間
Should I just call it quits?
我是不是應該見好就收
There is also a lot of documentation.
文書資料也很多
Travel expenses should be borne by oneself.
“出差費應自行負擔”
Charge your phone at home.
“手機充電應在家完成”
The Magic Bureau is extremely frugal.
魔導廳有夠小氣
This is the documentation for today.
這是今天的文書資料…
Botega and the Kingdom's army attacked Republic Gamma and retreated.
“伯特加與王國軍部隊 剛進攻剛瑪共和國 旋即撤退”
It is indeed difficult to suppress the enemy with our current strength.
“以我們平常的戰力 果然難以鎮壓敵人”
The key is…
“而關鍵就是…”
So you were the reason.
原來原因就是妳啊
No wonder I'm getting a headache similar to when I'm approaching low air pressure.
難怪我有一種 類似低氣壓接近時的頭痛感
Demon clan, what brings you here?
魔族 妳來這裡有何貴幹
Sixth of the seven tools,
七大道具之六
smoke bomb.
煙霧彈
Bang!
我敲
You have the audacity to do such a stupid thing.
妳竟敢做這種蠢事
But this is an unexpected gain.
不過這是意想不到的收穫
My deepest apologies, Chief Fred.
實在萬分抱歉 弗雷德長官
We actually let this suspicious person infiltrate the Magic Bureau.
我們居然讓這種可疑人士 成功入侵魔導廳
Let's contact the police first.
我們先聯絡警方吧
No, no need.
不 不需要
You go out first, don't let anyone in.
妳先出去 別讓任何人進來
Okay, just relax and answer my questions.
好了 妳就放輕鬆 回答我的問題吧
First, give me your name.
妳先報上妳的名字
I am a noble demon.
我是高貴的魔之眷屬
How can I tell a human my name?
豈能向人類自報名號
So you are a demon clan.
妳果然是魔族啊
Thank you for confirming that for me.
感謝妳讓我確認了這一點
T-This is bad.
糟…糟了
I miss the good old days.
真懷念
On the battlefield ten years ago, I saw a variety of demon clans.
我在十年前的戰場上 也見過形形色色的魔族
I have never seen a demon clan as adorable as you.
倒是頭一次看到 像妳這麼可愛的魔族
W-What is this?
這…這是怎樣
I won't fall for this trick.
我才不會被這招騙呢
Pardon me, I couldn't help but speak a few words.
失禮了 我忍不住說了幾句
What do you do and where do you live?
妳住哪裡 做什麼工作
Have you had enough? Are you looking down on me?
你夠了沒有 你是瞧不起我嗎
If you want to kill me, just do it.
你要殺我的話就快點動手
I would rather die
要我捨棄魔之眷屬的尊嚴而服從人類
than give up my demon dignity
我潔妮亞…
and submit to humans.
寧願去死
I see. Your name is Zenia.
原來如此 妳的名字是潔妮亞…
Damn, you tricked me into saying that.
糟糕 你太卑鄙了 居然套我的話
By the way, I'm Fred, the Magic Bureau Chief.
順便告訴妳 我是王國魔導廳長官 弗雷德
I should have introduced myself first.
我應該先自我介紹的
Sorry, I was rude again.
抱歉 我又失禮了
Of course I know about this.
這種事情我當然知道
Because you heroes are His Majesty's and our demons' enemies.
因為你們勇者一行人 是陛下與我等魔之眷屬的仇敵
You are our most hated enemies.
你們是我們最痛恨的對象
Isn't Your Majesty the Demon Lord?
妳們的陛下…魔王是吧
Although we are enemies, I can't help but admire him.
雖然我們是敵人 我還是不禁佩服他
You're here on the Demon Lord's orders, aren't you?
妳果然是奉魔王的命令而來的嗎
N-No.
不…不是喔
His Majesty has been asleep since you defeated him.
陛下被你們打倒後 至今仍在沉睡
I just came here out of curiosity.
我只是出於個人好奇心才來的…
Speaking of which, Zenia,
話說回來 潔妮亞妹妹
I believe I have seen you somewhere.
總覺得我好像在哪裡見過妳耶
What now? I won't say a word.
現在又是怎樣 我半個字都不會說了
Where have I seen you before?
我到底是在哪裡看過妳呢
That's right, I saw you here.
對了 我是在這邊看到的
Look.
妳看
Is this you?
這個人就是妳吧
What's with the photo? Did you take it sneakily? You're being indecent.
怎麼會有那張照片 是你偷拍的嗎 你太猥瑣了
This was on a trashy news site a while back.
這是三流新聞網站前陣子的報導
You are quite daring to run naked down the street.
妳還真是大膽 居然在大街上裸奔
Not that, I was a little drunk at the time.
不是那樣的 那時我有點喝醉…
I understand. When people are drunk, they can lose control.
我懂 人一喝醉就很容易失控
I'm sure you had a great time, and I wish I could have been there to see it.
想必妳們玩得很開心吧 我真想當場見識一下
HERO MAX AND A NAKED WOMAN PLAY TAG LATE AT NIGHT So you drank with this guy who was running?
(勇者麥克斯與裸女深夜玩鬼抓人) 那妳是跟這個逃跑的男人一起喝嗎
Uh…yes.
呃…沒錯
You met a jerk.
妳碰上了一個渣男呢
He got you drunk
把人灌得醉醺醺的
and then ran away like a coward.
又這麼窩囊地到處竄逃
I have no idea who this guy is,
雖然我不知道這是哪來的傢伙
but he seems like a complete coward.
但這男人真是個沒骨氣的廢物
Zenia, you must not be taken in by such a bad man.
妳千萬不能被這種爛人騙走 潔妮亞妹妹
Who is this man?
這個男人到底是誰
Um…I can't remember because I was so drunk.
這…我喝得很醉 不記得了
So you only met this man once?
所以妳跟這男的只見過這麼一次
Yes…
對…
But there's nothing between us.
不過我跟他之間沒什麼
I see…
這樣啊…
I am relieved to hear you say that.
聽妳這麼說 叔叔我也放心了
If you had a relationship with that poor, jobless old man, it will be difficult.
要是妳跟那種窮酸的無業臭老頭 發生關係了 那我可難辦了
How is that even possible? A guy like him…
那怎麼可能呢 像他那種…
Stop playing dumb.
妳少在那邊裝傻了
You really think I'm clueless?
妳真以為我毫不知情嗎
Answer me.
回答我
Why are you trying to get close to Max?
妳接近麥克斯 到底有什麼企圖
What kind of evil thoughts are you trying to instill in Max,
妳們這些骯髒的魔族
you dirty demon clan?
到底想灌輸麥克斯什麼邪念
Answer me!
回答我
Sorry to interrupt.
抱歉打斷您…
Minister Gremes has arrived, Chief Fred.
弗雷德長官 格雷姆斯大臣已抵達
Let him wait.
讓他等著
But…
但是…
He said he has pressing issues.
他說有重要的事要談
If you don't hurry over…
若您不趕快過去的話…
This handcuff has the ability to greatly suppress the wearer's magical power.
這副手銬能強烈抑制穿戴者的魔力
It means you can't do the magic you're best at.
這表示妳無法發動你們最擅長的魔法
Don't even consider fleeing.
妳休想趁機開溜
Chief.
長官
By any means, don't notify the police.
妳千萬不要通知警方
Keep an eye on her until I return, Lim.
在我回來前好好看著她 琳姆
Chief Fred,
弗雷德長官
sorry for interrupting your busy schedule.
抱歉在您百忙之中打擾
No problem.
不會
The minister appears to be very busy as well.
我看閣下也是忙得不可開交
Would you like to go on a date with me?
妳要不要跟我約會
I know a good place.
我知道一家不錯的店
N-No need, I'm really terrified.
不…不用了 我實在不勝惶恐
Chief Fred is here, minister.
閣下 弗雷德長官來見您了
Fred.
小弗雷德
It's been a long time since we last met.
我們好久沒見面了
Minister Gremes, I am honored that you have come to personally visit me.
勞駕第三大臣親自來訪 我真是備感光榮 格雷姆斯閣下
You've learned how to flatter.
你已經學會怎麼拍馬屁啦
I am over the moon.
叔叔超開心
What is the chief thinking?
長官究竟在想些什麼
He unusually handcuffs and interrogates the criminal without notifying the police.
他不將這件事不告訴警方 而是私下對犯人上銬問話 太不正常了
Isn't this the same as being imprisoned?
豈不是跟監禁沒兩樣
I was too careless.
我真是太大意了
I not only got caught, but I also leaked information by accident.
我不只被抓到 還不小心將情報說溜嘴
At the very least, I can't let them know that His Majesty has been resurrected.
至少不能被他們發現陛下已經復活了
His Majesty was only recently resurrected.
陛下現在才剛復活沒幾天
If the two sides go to war, His Majesty will undoubtedly be at a disadvantage.
萬一雙方開戰 陛下肯定是壓倒性不利
Anyway, I need to figure out how to get out of here first.
總之我現在要先設法逃離這裡
Ex-Excuse me.
不…不好意思
What's wrong with you?
妳怎麼了
I-I want to go to the bathroom.
我…我想去廁所
Sorry, I came to find you out of the blue.
抱歉啊 我臨時跑過來找你
How have you been recently?
你最近如何啊
Minister, please get to the point.
閣下 麻煩您直接說重點
After all, the chief took time out of his busy schedule to see you.
畢竟長官公務繁忙還特地撥空見您
Let's take a commemorative photo first.
我們先拍個紀念照
Smile, Fred.
笑一個 小弗雷德
Minister. Geez.
閣下 您真是的
TODAY I VISITED THE MAGIC BUREAU. A SELFIE WITH THE CHIEF Done.
(今天來魔導廳 我跟長官大人的合照) 我拍好囉
Your smile is great. You are indeed the chief.
你的笑容超讚 不愧是長官
How about it? This is an app that can change expressions.
如何阿 這是可以改變表情的App
I'm very sorry, Chief.
非常抱歉 長官
Don't immediately share the photo you took on social media.
你不要拍了照就立刻上傳到社群網站
Weren't we chastised the last time our itinerary was revealed?
上次我們 還因為行程曝光被炎上不是嗎
It's too late, I've already posted.
來不及了 我已經發文了
Your face looks pale.
你的臉色真差
Are you worried about Leo?
你在擔心雷奧嗎
Worried?
擔心
It is a matter of prestige and interest for the kingdom, which worries me.
這件事有關王國的威信和利益 這點確實令人擔心
This country was fantastic ten years ago.
這國家十年前真的很棒
Although we were much poorer than we are now.
雖然我們比現在貧困多了
You heroes defeated the Demon Lord.
你們勇者一行人打敗魔王
This country was full of vitality everywhere.
這個國家到處都充滿活力
How is Max doing?
麥克斯那小子過得好嗎
Are you still in touch with him, Fred?
你跟他還有來往嗎 小弗雷德
No, he's hopeless.
沒有 他已經無可救藥了
That's really lonely.
那還真是令人寂寞
Minister, I'll have dinner with you another day.
閣下 我改天再跟您吃頓飯…
Right, right. Sorry, sorry.
對了對了 抱歉抱歉
I need to get to the point quickly. Don't be angry.
我要趕快進入正題才行 你別生氣嘛
Geez.
真是的
You should have learned your lesson and stopped engaging in illegal invasion.
這次學到教訓 妳以後不可以再非法入侵了
It's so embarrassing.
真是太丟臉了
Are you okay? Sit down slowly.
還可以嗎 妳慢慢坐下來
My clothes.
我的衣服…
Let me help you take it off.
我來幫妳脫吧
The clothes you wear are really hard to take off.
妳穿的衣服還真難脫
Are you done? Then let me help you wipe.
好了嗎 那我來幫妳擦吧
Please press the warm water button for washing. The weakest.
麻煩幫我按溫水洗淨 最弱的
You are one stubborn female spy.
妳真是個任性的女間諜
Thank you very much.
非常謝謝
It would be bad if Fred came back.
弗雷德回來的話就不妙了
If he interrogates me again, I may say something about His Majesty.
要是再被他問一次話 陛下的事情我可能會說溜嘴
I have to escape before that.
我必須在那之前逃出去才行
Here you go. Please eat.
來 請吃吧
What do you want to eat next?
妳接下來想吃什麼
I want asparagus. Please wrap it in bacon.
我要吃蘆筍 請妳用培根捲起來
You're really a handful.
真拿妳沒辦法
If I want to escape, I have to get past her.
我要逃出去 就要設法闖過她這關
I really don't want to do this.
我真不想這麼做
First of all, thank you for letting Botega join.
首先 謝謝你讓伯特加同行
Regardless of the outcome… As you know.
雖然最終結果如你所知
Lucky for him, his injuries were not too bad.
幸好他的傷勢沒那麼嚴重
So,
話說回來
why are we stuck in this situation?
為何我們會陷入這種僵局呢
Leo bears sole responsibility.
一切責任都在雷奧身上
If he doesn't take matters into his own hands…
如果那個蠢蛋沒有自作主張…
But the Gamma region is barren.
可是啊 剛瑪地區鳥不生蛋
If the kingdom had welcomed Leo and his team with open arms
當雷奧等人發現大量魔礦脈時
when they discovered a large vein of magical ore…
假如當時王國 以最豐厚的待遇接納他們…
If we had done that, the kingdom's reputation would have suffered.
要是真的那麼做 王國的威信將一落千丈
He became enraged and even betrayed the kingdom after denying taking bribes.
他不承認收賄還惱羞成怒 擅自叛國
How could the kingdom forgive and accept such a person?
王國怎麼能夠原諒並接納那種傢伙
Fred,
小弗雷德
do you believe Leo is someone who would accept bribes?
你覺得雷奧是會收賄的人嗎
His brain capacity is limited.
他的腦容量確實沒那麼大
I agree.
我贊成
Leo was framed. Poor guy.
雷奧他是被陷害的 太可憐了
Nonetheless,
即使如此
his rebellion was rash and irrational.
他以那種方式叛國 根本是任性妄為
Yes.
是啊
He must not have expected the kingdom he trusted to doubt him.
他肯定萬萬沒料到 自己深信的王國會懷疑他
He can't stand it anymore.
他忍無可忍了吧
He is a noble and incorruptible man.
他是個高尚清廉的男人
In our eyes, he is overly bright.
在我們眼中反而太耀眼了
How should I put it?
我該怎麼形容呢…
Noble and incorruptible people
高尚清廉的人
usually expect the same from those around them.
往往強求周遭的人與自己一樣
The Republic Gamma will never develop smoothly.
剛瑪共和國絕對不可能順利發展
Fred, you probably won't agree.
那小弗雷德你大概不會贊成了
To be honest,
不瞞你說
I would like to propose a peace treaty to the Republic Gamma.
我想對剛瑪共和國提出和平協議
Many people in the kingdom understand Leo and the republic.
有許多王國國民 能夠理解雷奧與共和國
I believe that a peaceful approach will gain some traction.
我認為和平路線 能獲得一定程度的支持
More importantly, aside from self-defense,
更重要的是 以目前而言
the Republic Gamma hasn't directly harmed the kingdom.
剛瑪共和國除了自衛 並沒有直接危害王國
However, public opinion toward the kingdom is deteriorating.
但社會大眾對王國的觀感 反而越來越差
The kingdom's recognition of it as a nation is another matter.
王國要不要承認那裡是獨立國家 當然是另一回事
I only hope that both parties can take a step back.
我只是希望彼此各退一步
I hope we can end this peacefully without any disputes.
希望雙方能夠不起爭執 和平收場
What do you think?
你覺得呢
Are you serious?
您是認真的嗎
What do the other ministers say?
其他大臣怎麼說
The old lady said it's fine.
老婆婆說沒問題
After all, she has always spoiled Leo.
畢竟她一直都很寵雷奧
The others…
其他人…
I can only persuade them slowly.
我只能慢慢說服了
One step at a time.
一步一步來吧
The first priority is to temporarily halt military operations along the border.
首要之務就是 暫時終止在國境的武力進攻
I hope to have a free, peaceful, and helpful relationship in the future.
將來我想建立完全自由 和平又有建設性的交流關係
To achieve this, we need your help.
為達目的 我們不能少了你的協助
Because you are Leo's companion
因為你既是雷奧的夥伴
and have a lot of support in the kingdom.
在王國國民的支持率也相當高
I will just have to do it.
我只能硬著頭皮上了
Anyway, I need to remove these magic-suppressing handcuffs first.
總之我要先脫下這個抑制魔力的手銬
Fred made a mistake.
弗雷德犯了一個錯誤
I can't use magic in the first place.
我本來就不會用魔法
So I have already devised a solution to this problem.
因此我早就想好這種狀況的對策
The seventh of the seven tools I hide in my clothes,
我藏在衣服裡的七大道具之七
slippery lubricant.
滑溜溜潤滑油
ZENIA'S NEW MEDICINE Good, now I can…
(潔妮亞新藥) 好 這下子就能…
Pull it out smoothly.
順利地拔出來
Huh?
咦
What are you doing?
妳在做什麼
I am thirsty, so I thought I would have a sports drink.
我有點口渴 想說喝個運動飲料
There's no such thing as a sticky sports drink.
哪有這種黏答答的運動飲料
Listen.
妳聽好了
I'm a direct subordinate of Chief Fred.
我是弗雷德長官的直屬官員
I have some understanding of magic.
我多少也了解一點魔法
If you dare to scheme, I won't hesitate to use force.
妳敢動歪腦筋 我也不惜行使武力
I just don't want to do it.
我不想這麼做就是了
I won't take you to the bathroom either.
我也不會帶妳去洗手間了喔
Are you listening?
妳有沒有在聽
You can't break free like that.
妳那樣是掙脫不了的
Just behave.
妳乖乖聽話吧
Okay, I broke free.
好 我掙脫了
Ouch.
好痛
I forgot my feet were covered in them.
我都忘了腳也沾上了
It looks like you are not a typical Cosplay dork.
看來妳不是普通的Cosplay傻妞
I finally get what the chief is thinking.
我終於明白長官的想法了
You are a level A dangerous individual.
妳是A級危險人物
I am not going to let you go.
我絕對不會放妳走
Would you like to board my ship?
你願不願意坐上我的這艘船呢
Fred.
小弗雷德
Alright.
好吧
After all, Minister Gremes personally invited me.
畢竟是格雷姆斯閣下親自邀請
I will do my best.
我會盡我所能
You arrogant prince.
你這個傲嬌王子
-Gremes pats on the head. -Ouch. I'm not a prince…
-格雷姆斯摸摸頭 -好痛…我才不是王子…
Great, then I can rest assured.
太好了 那我就放心了
I'll talk to you in detail another day.
改天再找你詳談
I am sorry to disturb you at work.
實在抱歉 打擾你工作
Yeah, please hurry back.
就是說啊 請您趕緊回去吧
Chief, we really appreciate your time today.
非常感謝您今天撥空 長官
Goodbye.
掰囉
Are you going back, Minister Gremes?
您要回去了嗎 格雷姆斯大臣
You've worked hard, Minister Gremes.
閣下您辛苦了
See you next time.
下次見
Thanks.
謝啦
You certainly made a stir.
你還真是大鬧了一場
Are you satisfied, Miss Spy?
妳滿足了沒 間諜小姐
Don't worry.
放心吧
I can control my flames' smoke, temperature, and burning range.
我的火焰包含溫度 煙 就連燃燒範圍都能控制自如
I won't take your life.
我不會要了妳的命
I can't… breathe…
我沒辦法…呼吸…
I must put you to sleep for a little while.
我得請妳睡一下了
My consciousness…
我的意識…
That's great, Minister.
真是太好了 閣下
But the main show is just getting started.
不過重頭戲現在才要開始
What the minister said almost made me pass out.
大臣講的東西真是令我差點昏倒
Our next schedule is…
稍後我們的行程是…
Does anyone like it?
有沒有人按讚啊
First is the meeting attended by Deputy Minister Melbin.
首先是梅爾賓副大臣出席的會議
Then the plum viewing party…
再來是賞梅會…
Something has happened, Minister! The Magic Bureau…
出事了 閣下 魔導廳…
exploded!
發…發生爆炸了
No way.
不會吧
It's dangerous, you can't stop.
很危險耶 你不可以停下來
Drive away quickly, I don't want to get involved.
你快點開走 我不想被捲進去
It is a terrorist attack. Terrorist attack.
這是恐攻啦 恐攻
The Republic has finally taken action.
共和國還是出手啦
Now you're really in a tight spot.
這下子你就火燒屁股了
What would you do?
你會怎麼出招
Monk Fred.
僧侶弗雷德